Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Other Left Activism TAM.508
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Other Left Activism
2007-
TAM.508
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
0.001 linear feet (1+ websites; i.e., a collection of websites that grows on an ongoing basis)
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Alternative Mass Media, was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library. The Web Archiving Service was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The Tamiment Library creates topically based archives of websites documenting labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States. The collection contains periodically archived websites, with additional websites added on an ongoing basis, from which additional topically based web archives are created, of primarily U.S. Left entities (organizations and individuals) engaged in a variety of causes and issues, including civil and human rights, social and economic justice, and other issues. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Note: if a link does not work, click on the TITLE of this archive (in the "Description" section at the beginning of the finding aid) to access the archive, then use the site list to select the web site(s) you wish to view.
Tamiment Library.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
A list of related Tamiment Library web archives, whose ns2:titles all begin with the prefix "Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left)," can be found at the website Web Archives from New York University Libraries.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Other Left Activism, was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library. This service employs open source web archiving utilities developed by Internet Archive with the support of the The International Internet Preservation Consortium. The Web Archiving Service was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The role of the Tamiment Library during this project and thereafter was/is to create topically based archives of websites documenting contemporary and ongoing labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States.
Scope and Contents note
Contains periodically archived websites, with additional websites added on an ongoing basis, from which additional topically based web archives are created, of primarily U.S. Left entities (organizations and individuals) engaged in a variety of causes and issues, including civil rights, human rights, the internet and world wide web (related cultural, political, social, etc.) issues, progressive electoral politics, struggles for social and economic justice, including the anti-globalization, environmental, feminist and peace movements, and also including those working on behalf of immigrants, the LGBT community, and other groups and issues. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl.
Note: if a link does not work, click on the TITLE of this archive (in the "Description" section at the beginning of the finding aid) to access the archive, then use the site list to select the web site(s) you wish to view.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Arrangement
Websites arranged alphabetically.
Anti-globalization movement |z United States.; Civil rights |z United States.; Environmentalists |z United States.; Feminism |z United States.; Gay rights |z United States.; Green movement |z United States.; Human rights advocacy.; Human rights.; Immigrants |z United States |x Civil rights.; Iraq War, 2003- |x Moral and ethical aspects; Minorities |x Civil rights |z United States.; Peace movements |z United States.; Radicalism |z United States.; Social justice |z United States.; Third parties (United States politics); Women's rights |z United States.
- Other Left Activism Archive, 2007-
  - ABC No Rio, 02/08/2007-
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives, 11/21/2008-
  - ACORN (Organization), 02/07/07-
  - Act Up New York (Organization), 12/07/2008-
  - American Constitution Society, 09/29/2007-
  - American Friends Service Committee, 02/07/2007-
  - American Library Association. Social Responsibilities Roundtable, 11/24/2008-
  - Animal Liberation Front, 09/26/2007-
  - Assata Shakur, 07/28/2009-
  - Behind the Homefront, 10/03/2007-
  - Billionaires For Bush, 08/15/2009
  - Black Radical Congress, 08/14/2009-
  - Blackout Arts Collective, 10/03/2007-
  - The Brights' Net, 11/24/2008-
  - Center for Constitutional Rights, 05/07/08-
  - Center for Constitutional Rights NY, 2/7/2007
  - Center for Popular Economics (CPE), 10/27/09-
  - Community Voices Heard, 3/19/2010-
  - CorpWatch, 09/23/2007-
  - Critical Resistance, 09/23/2007-
  - Critical Sociology, 11/29/2008-
  - DRUM Desis Up and Moving, 09/29/2007-
  - Econ-Atrocity / Econ-Utopia » Field Guide to the U.S. Economy, 04/01/2009-
  - Experimental Party Disinformation Center, 05/10/2008-
  - Friends of the Earth International, 09/23/2007-
  - George Polk Awards in Journalism, 1/27/2010-
  - Green Party of New York State, 09/22/07-11/21/2008
  - Green Party of the United States, 05/07/2008-
  - Greenwich House, 08/21/2009-
  - Guerilla Girls, 09/29/2007-
  - Guthrie, Woody, 1912-1967, 8/15/2009-
  - Harry Hay, 07/31/2009
  - Howard Zinn, 6/30/2010-
  - Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, 03/18/2009-
  - Immigrant Solidarity Network, 09/28/2007-
  - Institute for Social Ecology, 09/23/2007-
  - Interactivist Network, 02/08/2007-
  - International Endowment for Democracy, 07/31/2009-
  - Jubilee USA, 09/28/2007-
  - Klein, Naomi, 1970-, 10/01/07-
  - Kucinich, Dennis, 1946-, 09/28/2007-
  - Labor Party (U.S.), 02/07/07-
  - Left Forum, 5/6/2010-
  - Living Liberally, 12/23/2008-
  - MADRE(Organization), 12/24/2008-
  - May First/People Link, 03/15/2009-
  - Metropolitan Council on Housing (New York, N.Y.), 03/16/2009-
  - Michael Parenti Political Archive, 07/29/2009-
  - Moore, Michael, 12/24/2008-
  - Nader, Ralph, 02/07/07-
  - National Lawyers Guild, 02/08/07-
  - National Organization for Women, 09/28/07-
  - National Organization for Women, New York City, 09/30/07-
  - National War Tax Resistance Coordinating Committee, 09/28/2007-
  - New York Collective of Radical Educators, 10/01/2007-
  - North Star Fund, 12/23/08-
  - People for the American Way, 10/10/2007-
  - Proliberated Freedom Campaign, 9/28/2007-12/23/2008
  - Radical Homosexual Agenda, 03/07/2009-
  - Radical Philosophy Association, 11/29/2008-
  - Radical Reference, 11/24/2008-
  - Reverend Billy & The Church of Life After Shopping, 10/01/2007-
  - School of the Americas Watch (Organization), 09/28/2007-
  - Sista II Sista, 09/29/2007-
  - Southern California Library, 11/24/2008-
  - Students Against Sweatshops, 02/07/2007-
  - Students for a Democratic Society, 09/28/2007-
  - Students for a Free Tibet, 10/03/2007-
  - Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University, 05/07/2008-
  - The Icarus Project, 5/8/2011-
  - The Struggle for Free Speech at CUNY, 1931-1942, 07/31/2009
  - Time's Up NYC Direct Action Environmental Organization, 10/01/07-
  - TradeJustice New York Metro (formerly NYC People's Referendum on Free Trade), 07/26/2009
  - Union for Radical Political Economics, 11/29/2008-
  - Union Square Awards, 8/1/2011-
  - United for Peace and Justice (Organization), 02/07/2007-
  - Vote Rev Billy For Mayor Of NYC, 12/14/2009-
  - War Resisters League, 10/01/2007-
  - William Kunstler: Disturbing the Universe, 07/22/2009-3/14/2010
  - Working Families Party (N.Y.), 02/07/2007-